Hello everyone, the topic I would like to share with you today is 3D virtual technology,
how to be creative and sustainable.
First of all, I would like to apologize because today's presentation is in English.
I was too busy with work and didn't have time to translate it into Chinese.
But I will try my best to make it clear, and I will have time to ask questions at the end.
First of all, let me introduce myself. My name is Wang Chen, also known as Clara.
I graduated from the Department of Fashion Design at the University of London.
I also studied fashion and finance with a French teacher for a period of time,
so I was born with a background in design.
In 2017, as a 3D designer, I joined the H&M Creative Lab
and worked with all H&M brands and categories.
I studied and worked there until I became a senior.
Today, as a business expert, I joined the company's business tech.
Now I am mainly responsible for everything related to 3D.
We hope to use my previous experience to accelerate the digital transformation and the use of new technologies in the company.
Let me briefly introduce H&M, because I guess not everyone knows us very well.
We have been in Sweden since 1947.
We started our first H&M store in the city of Westeros.
H&M Group has been a global fashion enthusiast for 73 years.
We are a brand family.
Apart from H&M, we also have COS, Other Stories, ARKIT, MONKEY, WEEKDAY, H&M HOME, and A-FUND.
Apart from WEEKDAY and A-FUND, we can buy everything else in China.
We hope to provide fashion design and service to our customers in an exciting and sustainable way.
We want to bring inspiration and personal style to our customers.
With the rapid change in fashion sales and the COVID-19 pandemic,
we have accelerated the development of digital and integrated channels.
We have improved our work methods and become more flexible, fast and efficient.
All of this is to meet the constant needs of our customers.
As our customers' expectations continue to increase,
it means that we need to work more passionately.
Our goal is to provide the best combination of fashion, quality, price, and sustainability.
I would like to focus on the sustainable development vision of our group.
We want to be a fair and equal enterprise,
leading the change in fashion to the cycle and the climate.
Our sustainable development work covers the entire value chain.
We focus not only on our own operations,
but also on the interests of other stakeholders and the entire industry.
Our global sustainable development team has a total of 270 employees.
It is one of the largest sustainable development organizations in this industry and in other industries.
We believe that we need enough people and power to promote this sustainable development work
and lead the change in the industry.
In fact, from the very beginning,
the mission of H&M Group was to democratize fashion.
Today, this means that it is sustainable.
This is the only way we can provide fashion and design to all our customers.
Based on our vision,
the three key areas of our sustainable development strategy are
100% cycle and climate positivity,
100% fairness and equality,
and 100% leadership change.
In the future, I believe that the future of H&M Group will be much brighter.
Now we will move on to the next part of the H&M Group's vision,
which is the H&M industry's digital technology.
This is actually an important part of sustainable development.
As you can see in the background,
this is our first attempt three years ago.
This is a milestone of our product integration technology.
As you can see,
As you can see, we started from fabric simulation.
From 2014 to 2017, we mainly simulated wool, silk, and lace fabrics.
The 2D simulation here is actually different from the ordinary 2D surface.
The fabric we simulate will also produce a technical package directly,
which is a tech pack, which can be produced directly at the factory.
So this is a technical plus design step.
At the same time, the professional knowledge of this team of designers actually has higher requirements.
After having the fabric, in 2017, we started to try 3D fabric.
We started from 3D needle fabric to 3D shrink fabric, 3D wool fabric, 3D socks and hats,
and then we went on to wool clothes, underwear, and so on.
Then we expanded to more and more different types.
As we expanded, we introduced new talents, technology, and equipment.
So on this picture,
actually,
we included at least four to five software and equipment.
You might ask, what did we try in 2019 to 2020?
But I can't share this with you today.
Regarding avatar,
I believe everyone here is a user,
so everyone knows that avatar refers to the platform in our reality.
So after the clothing industry started to use 3D technology,
the necessary elements in reality needed to be digitized.
This is our so-called digital twin.
Ideally, we certainly hope that the digital world can truly simulate the real world,
and even predict the real world.
So the correct size of the avatar is actually very important,
because with it, you can do real, effective 3D simulation in the business.
Next, I will introduce a few applications under different scenarios.
First of all, this is a T-shirt of a girl from H&M and a shirt of a boy.
Through this 3D virtual technology,
we can try and display different colors,
patterns, and patterns without any food.
And then during the design process,
we can boldly try different proportions and combinations.
So in fact,
if the designer might have to print it out in the past,
put it on the food,
and compare it,
it might be wrong to print it again.
So this kind of long process can now be done directly in the 3D system.
And then for the designers who are very familiar with the style,
basically they can make the decision to order directly.
This is the next talk I will be conducting.
Because it is online.
Can they hear your voice?
Is it because of your PPT?
Yes, it is.
It helps me.
And then the next one is,
this is a demonstration of the same style,
the same pattern,
and the different lines of sand,
the different base.
Of course,
we also first simulated the 2D fabric,
and then simulated the 3D layer.
In fact,
as long as the reading is clear enough,
the buyer and the designer can also make the decision directly.
So this is a demonstration of the 3D full pattern of Coskits,
the print of the print,
and the display of the 3D full pattern of Coskits.
Of course,
first of all,
you need to have the full pattern of this avatar to be realized.
And then,
we currently only recommend using it to see the overall proportion of the clothes
and the proportion of the print,
including the position on the clothes.
Because you may find that some designs look good with small patterns,
and after enlarging,
you may not be able to see them.
So,
But at the moment,
we actually found that there may still be some limitations
when it comes to the fitting of the 3D set.
And then this is a series of our exhibitions.
What this picture shows is our brand,
MONKEY,
in 2018,
a bag series.
This is also the first brand of H&M Group
to try to simulate the whole series with 3D.
And then on the picture,
it simply shows some of our cooperation at the time.
it shows some of our cooperation at the time.
You may know that this collection line-up is usually made up of 2D exactly,
or photos.
Normally,
the process is not that intuitive.
It's only possible to have the sample image in the photo.
So,
the whole series can be clearly displayed in 3D at an early stage,
The whole series can be clearly displayed in 3D at an early stage,
and this is the concept of the collection,
and also the colors,
and the pattern ratio,
saving us a lot of sample time.
In fact,
a lot of our online buyers
saw the whole 3D series,
and basically took all the orifices.
a lot of our online buyers saw the whole 3D series,
同样是Collection,这是Other Stories AOA Team的一次大胆尝试,他们是从设计到打样到试衣全部是基于3D模拟,快速设计,快速决策,其中相对简单的款式我们就直接在3D上模拟实穿,比较复杂的款式我们通过VSR进行实穿,所以这整个系列只打了一轮的15样。
再补充一下,这些全部都是通过远程完成的,所以这当中其实是少不了还有跟单同时的一些协调和沟通。
3D虚拟技术还有一个非常大的好处,就是可以积累数字资产。
一件衣服一旦建成,它是可以用来分享,然后重复使用的。
下一个season,其实你只要简单的修改或者更换颜色和印花就可以了。
当你的数字资产累积的越来越大,你的效率就会越来越高,然后节约的实物打样非常的环保。
总的来说,3D虚拟技术的好处是非常显而易见的。
以前大家可以看到我们是从一个想法一直到最终我们的顾客可以买到我们的产品,这中间会经历非常非常多人的sample。
从prototype到development到quotation到size-set到communication到counter-sample,还有最后production-sample。
那其实我们要注意的是,我们是希望3D虚拟技术减少从prototype-sample一直到size-set-sample中间的这个实物样。
这里说的是减少,不是取代。
然后前期呢,就是这些benefit大家可以看,前期当然从设计上它真的是一个颠覆性的一个设计的过程。
那在开发的过程中,它也很明显地缩短了我们的开发时间,增加了准确性,节省了非常多的实物样。
然后在沟通上,它其实非常的直接,它是一个视觉化的沟通,所以减少了很多当中可能会产生的误解,然后更快地去做决定。
那当然基于可持续的话,它是非常环保的,因为你不需要打非常多的physical sample。
但同时其实3D虚拟技术我也有它的局限。
那其实我们看到,我们发现就是,其实你可以在3D上对于颜色,你可以做一个stories的decision,就是你可以决定你今年想做什么颜色。
但其实大家知道不同的颜色在不同的材质上显示出来的是不一样的。
所以当你决定了你今年要下单的颜色,至于它到底是哪一种程度的红或者哪一种程度的蓝,其实还是需要去打颜色的。
所以这一步其实是无法省略的。
那包括像sequence,就是猪片,这些比较复杂的材料,就我们发现其实你用3D做,如果你想达到一模一样的这个效果,你用3D做,其实花的时间是远远高于我们的供应商直接给我们15样的一个反馈时间。
所以基于这个,我们其实还是决定某些比较复杂的材料,我们还是会去打15样。
所以这是一个平衡的一个过程。
那关于就是内衣,内衣我们现在目前为止只是把它用来做一个审美上的一个决定,暂时无法做任何的就是技术上的一个试衣,一个fitting。
这是我们正在做的这个transformation,这个转变。
那其实首先大家都知道fashion这个行业可能100多年都没有什么变化,那目前其实最明显的就是我们的工具开始产生了变化。
其实就是过去的工具,大家可以看到人台,我们的立刻系统打板,还有我们的实物面料,那现在我们的工具慢慢的会变成了我们人台变成了一个虚拟人台。
那我们的pattern可能会有新的其他的软件开始直接跟3D软件去对接打pattern。
然后我们的面料其实也是用虚拟直接去设计,然后加那个生产。
那这里特别要说的一点就是3D的虚拟样品它不是独立存在的,所以说也不是说你3D做得越漂亮就是越好。
我们所谓的打引号的好的一个3D虚拟样衣,其实它需要和实物进行样品的验证。
是没有经过验证的3D其实它没有那么的,中文怎么说,
就是可以可以直接让你做决定。
所以其实3D和实物样不是一个相互替代的过程,它们是相互依存的这么一个关系。
那最后我再分享一下就是我们学到的一些经验吧,然后可以简单概括为就是技术3D的虚拟技术先决条件,当中会有硬件软件,还有就是你需要的和行业相关的这个知识和经验。
这些你必须要去了解。
其次是流程,那其实你要明白就是你花进去的时间和你真正想要得到的一个结果,这中间的一个平衡。
然后对于就是现有的这个流程,你的最佳的嵌入方式是什么。
然后其次就是人,其实人还是非常非常的关键的。
那首先对于这个新的技术,你要想办法尝试去建立起这个信任。
因为我们也会发现很多新技术一开始的推进呢,很多时候会受到一些伤害。
然后其实信任的建立非常非常的重要。
然后其次再是adoption,再是去适应。
然后再是去慢慢可能会有新的工作上的function的一些转变。
然后还是,就是它还是需要involve,它不是一个单独的软件,你说你的数字化转型,不是一个3D软件就可以完成的。
它其实是需要就是人,还有产品,还有很多方面的,大家像一个团队一样共同的。
然后去共同去推动。
然后最后包括你必须要有一个一个中央的一个就是清楚的一个架构,去管理你的这些所有的3D。
包括你的储存系统,你的跟踪系统,然后这些其实都还是需要花非常多的时间和人力去做的。
所以其实数字化转型它确实是需要一个团队是full time去做这件事情的。
嗯。
那我今天的分享就到这里。
然后谢谢大家。
然后我们今天团队的那个Sovia,Cloris,思佳也来到了现场。
然后大家一会儿也可以找他们去交流。
那大家如果有什么问题想要问Clara的话,可以举手提问一下。
谢谢你的分享。
想一个问题就是你们HM的官网上,如果是一些详情页会用3D的一些照片吗,还是会实物开造?
这个算公司机密吧。
但是不能告诉你。
但是其实可以分享,比如说你知道其实像一家的官网,他们所有的东西都是CG图片。
都是模拟出来的。
The pattern you're creating for, are you using additional structure pattern or you're then using another to this 2D software for the building pattern?
其实是,我们,pattern makers,也会在Lectra里面创造,然后再放在Clow里面。
所以他们目前还没有直接在Clow里面创造。
那个问题是,你可能需要一些改变在3D上,那你怎么转移这些改变到实物上?
嗯,那是一个很好的问题。
所以如果你想要改变你的产品,通过你的设计过程。
所以其实我们也训练了我们的企业人。
所以我们需要我们的企业人来改变它们在3D上,一起与我们的设计团。
谢谢。
还有想要提问吗?
想说,我的问题是,你认为哪些是Main-Dialog的企业人我们认识?
What is the efficiency of how many pieces they can make or something like that?
Do you monitor that kind of reports?
What is the efficiency of one supplier in creating a sample?
The efficiency really depends on the complexity or the familiarity of our supplier.
So we have different level of supplier.
That's what my question is.
Do you level that?
Because in production, we do compare all those efficiency and everything.
Because this kind of a digital sample, right?
So maybe comparing the same product complexity.
Do you guys think about it or you have plans to do something in that direction?
We are on our way to it.
We are trying to build a kind of system trying to help us to evaluate.
So I just can say we are on our way.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Welcome.
Great presentation.
Thank you.
Clara, sorry, I have another question.
Because we are also doing this.
It's okay. It's okay. You are the first.
Thank you.
I really understand.
I want to ask, in the whole supply chain,
how many years do you expect it to last?
How many years do you think it will take to use this product in the industry?
How do you standardize it?
How do you standardize the production process and communication process?
This is really...
We do have a vision.
But I can't say it now.
But I also...
To be honest, this estimate...
We can't say that our estimate is accurate.
But we do have a timeline.
We have a vision.
We hope to lead to...
For example, by the end of this year,
we hope we can...
Just like our sustainability,
we also have a very clear vision.
For example, by 2023,
we hope all our fabrics will be environmentally friendly.
Yes, we have a vision.
But I can't say it now.
Thank you.
Actually, my question is related to the previous question.
Because she asked what kind of fabric it is.
I just want to ask about the development phase.
H&M is now in the development phase.
Using this...
How much do you want to reduce the amount of food?
As you just saw,
actually, reducing the amount of food is not a goal.
It is an editing effect.
Especially when you try...
H&M is such a big company.
Especially when you try a new software,
it is actually very careful.
So, so far, we are just going to calculate.
We hope it can reduce the amount of food as much as possible.
It's not that our goal is to reduce the amount of food.
But you just saw that we have a lot of sample runs.
We hope we can take at least one to two sample runs out.
Like this.
Yes.
Thank you.